mineweb.com 2016-06-20

# Privacy policy - Mineweb

**1\. Privacy policy**

This privacy policy is complimentary to, and should be read and understood together with, the general terms and conditions of use of Moneyweb Holdings Limited, all of its stakeholders, subsidiaries the subsidiaries of Moneyweb Holding’s subsidiaries and respective holding companies, the subsidiaries of such holding companies, divisions and affiliates (“Moneyweb”).

**2\. The General Principles of our Privacy Policy**

2.1 This privacy policy covers how we treat your personal information collected electronically when you use the Moneyweb website (the “Site”), register or apply online for any Moneyweb products or services, or when you contact Moneyweb electronically.

2.2 Moneyweb respects your privacy and your personal information and for this reason, we take care to protect your personal information and to keep it confidential.

2.3 When dealing with your personal information we apply the following –

2.3.1 Moneyweb will only disclose, collate and process your personal information with your express written permission unless we are legally required to do so.

2.3.2 Moneyweb will not use your personal information for any other purpose, other than that which we disclosed to you, unless you give Moneyweb your express written permission to do so, or unless Moneyweb is permitted or required to do so by law.

2.3.3 By using the Site, registering or applying online for any Moneyweb products or services, or contacting Moneyweb electronically, you provide Moneyweb with your express written permission to share your personal information within Moneyweb, in the ordinary course of Moneyweb′s business, including for purposes of providing you with the relevant products and services. You may revoke this consent in writing at any time.

**3\. What do we mean by Personal Information**

Personal information refers to information that identifies or relates specifically to you, for example, your name, age and identity number or any other information you use to register for the website and all related information will also be regarded as personal information.

**4\. How we collect your Personal Information**

Whenever you use the Site, complete an application form, contact Moneyweb electronically, or use one of the products, services, facilities, tools or utilities offered by Moneyweb on the Site, Moneyweb will collect your personal information.

**5\. Why we collect and use Personal Information**

5.1 In order to make your use of the Site and the products, services, facilities, tools or utilities offered on the Site as informative and successful as possible, it is necessary for Moneyweb to find out exactly what you need and want. The following are some of the reasons (i.e. disclosed reasons) why Moneyweb would collect your personal information –

5.1.1 for Moneyweb to process your instructions or requests;

5.1.2 for Moneyweb to ensure that we meet your needs, Moneyweb may collect and analyse your personal information and combine all the information that we have about you for research and statistical purposes. We may also use your personal information to personalise and tailor our services to meet your needs;

5.1.3 once Moneyweb has collected and analysed your personal information, Moneyweb may send you promotional material or details which we think may be of interest to you subject to applicable laws;

5.1.4 to conduct market research; and

5.1.5 to conduct academic research. This research is conducted to evaluate and improve Moneyweb’s product offerings. You are advised that information may be shared with third parties such as academics and researchers. All information collected for research purposes will be kept strictly confidential and all data will be depersonalised. No personal information will be made available to a third party without your written consent. If we publish the results of this research, you will not be identified by name.

5.2 Your privacy is important to us and we will therefore not sell, rent or provide your personal information to unauthorised third parties for their independent use, without your consent. If at any stage after you have given Moneyweb your consent, you no longer wish Moneyweb to use or share your personal information, you may at any stage withdraw your consent.

5.3 You accept that we may store your personal information outside of the region or country that you may submit or use it in.

**6\. Protection of your Personal Information**

6.1 Moneyweb values the information that you choose to provide and will take reasonable steps to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or unauthorised alteration. The information Moneyweb has, concerning Moneyweb clients, is stored in databases that have built-in safeguards to ensure the privacy and confidentiality of that information.

6.2 When you use the products, services, facilities, tools or utilities provided by Moneyweb on the Site, you may be given an access number, user name, password and/or personal identification number (“PIN”). You must always keep your user name, access card, password and/or PIN a secret and ensure that you do not disclose it to anyone.

**7\. Correction of Personal Information**

If you ever want to update or correct any of your personal information held by Moneyweb, you can e-mail us or you can phone our contact centre.

**8\. Personal Information held by or disclosed by you or Moneyweb to a third party**

Because Moneyweb is not responsible for any representations or information or warranties or content on any third party website (including third party websites linked to the Site, websites facilitated by us or websites that serve as social networks like Facebook or Twitter), Moneyweb does not exercise control over the privacy policies of these third parties and you should refer to the privacy policy of these third parties to see how they protect your privacy.

**9\. Cookies**

Moneyweb uses cookies. The word “cookie” refers to information that is sent from the Site to your hard drive, where it is saved. In this way, the next time you use the Site, Moneyweb will know who you are and that you have visited the Site before. We also collect information about how you use the website, your preferences and past browsing history.

**10\. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

10.1 Moneyweb may amend this privacy policy from time to time. Moneyweb will give you notice of any material changes within a reasonable time, however, we recommend that you familiarise yourself with this privacy policy regularly.

10.2 The current version of this privacy policy will govern the respective rights and obligations between you and Moneyweb each time that you access and use the Site.

**11\. Which laws apply to this Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy is governed by the laws of the Republic of South Africa, and you consent to the jurisdiction of the South African courts in respect of any dispute which may arise out of or in connection with the formation, interpretation, substance or application of this privacy policy.
